Kentucky Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty; Records apap401
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Legislative Activities, 1992-2023
  - 2020 Legislation
    - Kentucky Alliance for the Seriously Mentally Ill Exclusion Act, House Bill 237, Talking Points with Poll Data, 2020 January 14
    - KCADP Letter to Membership to Take Action, 2020 January 14
    - Tennessee Alliance for the Severe Mental Illness Exclusion (TASMIE) Fact Sheet, 2020 January 14
    - Possible Questions and Responses for Senate Bill 17 at Senate Judiciary Hearing, 2020 January 21
    - Targeted Legislators List, 2020 January 28
    - Draft testimony for Julie Regarding Senate Bill 154, 2020 February 26
    - Committee Report, Regular Session 2020 Senate Committee on Health and Welfare, 2020 February 27
    - Photograph After Vote, 2020 February 27
    - Unofficial Copy of the SB 154, 2020 March 2
    - Unofficial Copy of the SB 154 with Amendment Language, 2020 March 5
    - Graphic for Twitter Prompting Viewers to Vote Yes for SB 154, 2020 March 7
    - Graphic for Twitter Prompting Viewers to Vote Yes for SB 154, with Number to Contact State Senator, 2020 March 8
    - Unofficial Copy of the HB 148 Bill Text, 2021 January 6
    - Photo of Rep. Chad McCoy and the Vote on HB 148, 2021 March 1
    - House of Reprsentatives 2021 Regular Session, Vote on HB 148, An Act Relating to Mental Illness, 2021 March 1
    - Jewish Homily for Shabbath, 2021 March 6
    - Op-Ed Draft for Gutmann, 2022 January 5
    - Poll Results for Question: "Do you Support or Oppose the Death Penalty for Persons with Severe Mental Illness?", 2018 December
    - House Bill, An Act Relating to Serious Mental Illness, 2020 January
    - Death Penalty: Serious Mental Illness Bills, Myths and Misconceptions v. Facts, 2019
    - House 2021 General Assembly Anticipated Votes
    - House Bill 148 Serious Mental Illness, Letter, 2021
    - House Bill 148 Serious Mentall Illness, 2021
    - American Bar Association, Adopted by the House of Delegates, Recommendation, 2006 August 7-2006 August 8
  - 2022 Legislation
    - "82 Percent of Kentucky Voters Oppose the Death Penalty for Persons with Severe Mental Illness" Chart for social media, 2019 February 6
    - Committee Report Regular Session, Senate Committee on Judiciary HB 148, 2021 March 4
    - Thoughts on Upcoming General Assembly and Organizing Beforehand, 2021 July 23
    - Bill Request 323 with New Language, 2021 November 18
    - House Bill 237 Talking Points with Poll Data, 2022 January 5
    - West and Wheeler Constituents of Stephen West, 2022 January 7
    - Bill Request 323, Final Version, 2022 January 8
    - A Statistical Overview of the Kentucky Death Penalty Report, 2022 January 11
    - Wheeler Constituents, Pike County, 2022 January 12
    - Wheeler Constituents, 2022 January 12
    - House Bill 269 Desacription from Kentucky Committee to End Executions, 2022 January 18
    - List of Cosponsor Twittter Handles, 2022 January 19
    - "Kentucky Alliance for the Seriously Mentally Ill Exclusion Act" House Bill 269 Description and Logo, 2022 January 22
    - Letter from Pat Delahanty Regarding Strategy for Senate Vote for House Bill 269, to End Executions of Severely Mentally Ill Persons, 2022 January 31
    - Pat Delahanty and Representative Photograph, 2022 February 3
    - Letter from Pat Delahanty, List of Senators Matched to Parishes, 2022 February 6
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky House of Representatives Regular Session, Vote on HB 269, 2022 February 9
    - Photograph of Rep. Chad McCoy, 2022 February 9
    - Senate List and Interview Results, 2022 February 17
    - Newsmax.com Article,"Official: CPAC Death Penalty Debate Shows Conservative Opposition Growing", 2022 February 25
    - Senator Twitter Handles List, 2022 February 28
    - Message to Constituents Regarding House Bill 269, 2022 March 5
    - Strategy to Contact Senators, 2022 March 7
    - Justice Research Group 2022 Poll, "Do you support or oppose your local prosecutor seeking a death sentence against a person with a diagnosed mental illness?" Graphic, 2022 March 10
    - Photograph of Parolin, 2022 March 13
    - "Kentucky Senate passes bill to prevent mentally-ill receiving death sentence" Article Fox 56 News, 2022 March 27
    - Poll Results for Question "Do you Support or Oppose the Death Penalty for Persons with Severe Mental Illness", 2018 December
    - Mason-Dixon Kentucky Poll Results for "Question: Do you support or oppose the death penalty for persons with severe mental illness?", 2018 December
    - Mason-Dixon Kentucky Poll Information for Rep. Heavrin, 2018 December 12-2018 December 15
  - 2023 Legislation
    - Senate Bill 202, 2014 Regular Session, Unofficial Web Version, 2014 March 5
    - Corrections Impact Statement, for Senate Bill 202, 2022 March 26
  - Abolition 2002
    - Wall Street Journal Article "Cost of the Death Penalty", 2002 January 9
    - Woodbine Community Legislative Visit - Frankfort, 2002 January 24
    - Letter to Representative Urging to Vote "Yes" for Floor Amendment to House Bill 610, 2002 March 6
    - Letter to Members of the Free Conference Committee for House Bill 507 Regarding the Amendment from Pat Delahanty, 2002 March 30
    - Lexington Herald-Leader Article "Former Death Row Inmate Acquitted, Testimony of Drowned Witness Not Allowed in Retrial", 2002 August 2
    - Email News Article "Catholic Conference Applauds jury's Decision in Death Row Case", 2002 August 2
    - The Courier-Journal News Article "Man Sent to Death Row is Acquitted in Retrial, Original Conviction Thrown Out on Appeal; Defendant was 17 When Whitley Couple Slain", 2002 August 2
    - The Courier-Journal News Article "Some in Whitley Convinced Man Got Away with Murder Acquittal Angers Community, Jellico residents Who Knew Victims Say Verdict Wrong", 2002 August 3
    - The Courier-Journal Opinion/Editorial "Justice Without Death", 2002 September 7
    - Off the Record Article "Why not Get Bill Clinton's Reaction?", 2002 September 23
    - Messenger-Inquirer News Article "Where Does Lying End and the Truth Begin?", 2002 September 25
    - The Kentucky Post News Article On Govenor Patton, 2002 September 28
    - Meeting Notes with VI Miller, Secretary, Cabinet for Families and Children, 2002 October 8
    - The Courier-Journal News Article "Supreme Court Declines to Hear Death-Row Case. Stanford's Petition to Ban Execution because he was 17 at Time Still Active", 2002 October 8
    - KCADP Press Release "KCADP Urges Govenor to Commute Kevin Stanford's Death Sentence", 2002 October 21
    - Letter to Govenor Patton Asking to Commute the Death Sentence of Kevin Stanford from Pat Delahanty, 2002 October 23
    - The Courier-Journal News Article "Death Penalty for Juvenile Opposed, Poll Shows. Results Released as Patton Ponders Stanford Case", 2002 October 25
    - Lexington Herald-Leader Article "Poll: Death Penalty for Juvenile Unpopular, Most Kentuckians Would Change Law", 2002 October 26
    - Email News Alert- Kentucky Post Op-Ed on Juvenile Death Penalty, 2002 October 30
    - Lexington Herald-Leader Article "Age Focus of Death Penalty Debate, Man's Life Marked by Horrible Abuse", 2002 November 5
    - The Courier-Journal News Article "Lawmakers Urge Commutation of Stanford's Death Sentence", 2002 November 13
    - Letter to Govenor Patton Regarding Kevin Stanford, 2002 December 5
    - General Election Analysis, 2002
    - House Floor Amendment Abolition, 2002
    - Swift Justice in Maysville, 2002
    - Notes for the Abolition Bill, 2002
    - House Bill 407 "We Cannot Risk Executing Mentally Retarded Persons", 2002
    - Moatorium Bill "We Cannot Risk Executing the Innocent! Support the Moratorium on Executions!", 2002
    - Support House Bill 447 and Senate Bill 127 Flyer, Draft, 2002
    - Support House Bill 447 and Senate Bill 127 Flyer, Final in Word, 2002
    - Daily Independent Editorial "Govenor's Admitted Infidelity Threatens to Overshadow his Accomplishments", 2002
    - Hopkinsville Editor Against Patton "Honesty is Always the Best Policy", 2002
    - "Patton Prudent in Clearing his Political Docket" Article, 2002
    - Letter to Representative asking to Vote "Yes" to Floor Amendment to House Bill 610, 2002
    - Juvenile Death Penalty Presentation, 2002
    - Juvenile Death Penalty Information Fact Sheet, 2002
    - Call to Action, Tell Govenor Patton to Grant Kevin Stanford Clemency, 2002
    - "Dangerousness and the Death Penalty: An Examination of Juvenile Homicides in Kentucky" Report, 2002
  - Abolition 2003
    - Juvenile Death Penalty Group Members, 2003 January 10
    - Remarks for Louisville, Kentucky News Conference, 2003 January 14
    - "KCADP Praises Govenor Ryan and calls on Legislatiors to Keep Fixing Broken System" Press Release, 2003 January 14
    - The Courier-Journal News Article "Efforts to Ban Juvenile Death Sentences Praised Michigan Judge Applauds Kentucky Lawmakers' Bills", 2003 January 15
    - Campaign Slogan, 2003 January 16
    - Letter from KCADP Urging Catholic Parishes to help Pass Sentat Bill 15 and House Bill 180, 2003 January 16
    - The Courier-Journal Op-Ed "Stumbo-ling Around", 2003 January 25
    - "Too Young" Ad for the Rally to Stop Killing Kids, 2003 February 5
    - Juvenile Death Penalty Fact Sheet for Rally to Stop Killing Kids, 2003 February 5
    - The Colaition to Stop Killing Kids Rally Flyer, 2003 February 5
    - NCAAP Invitation to Rally in front of State Capital Building, 2003 February 5
    - The Abolish List News Article for New York, Ohio, and Illinois, 2003 May 9
    - General Abolition Bill Handout for House Bill 472, 2003
    - Fundraising List of KCADP Members, 2003
    - Judiciary Committee Vote Count Check, 2003
    - Juvenile Death Penalty Information, Senate Bill 15, House Bill 180, 2003
    - Media Advisory "American Bar Association President-Elect Supports Kentucky Bill to End Death Penalty for Juveniles", 2003
    - Juvenile Death Penalty Fact Sheet, 2003
    - Lobbying Your Representatives Fact Sheet, 2003
    - Letter of Request to Susan Sarandon from Pat Delahanty, 2003
    - Fax to Sister Helen Prejean from Pat Delahanty, 2003
    - KCADP Request for Help from NCADP, 2003
    - KCADP Rally Pledge Card, 2003
    - Postcard for Rally and Visits, 2003 February
    - Members of the House and Senate Judiciary Committees; and 2002 Cosponsors, 2002-2003
  - Abolition 2004
    - Judiciary Committee Members Votes with Pat's Corrections, 2001 March 1
    - Email from the Mailing List for People Working to Abolish the Death Penalty, "News: Illinois, Florida, Kansas", 2003 June 15
    - Email from the Mailing List for People Working to Abolish the Death Penalty, "Library Round Tables", 2003 July 14
    - The Courier-Journal Op-Ed "Taping Interrogations", 2003 July 20
    - Memoradum from Catholic Conference of Kentucky Regarding Kentucky General Assembly Joint Judiciary Committee Meeting, Barbourville, 2003 August 30
    - "Prosecutorial Resistance to Exculpatory DNA Evidence--Why We Must" News Article, 2003 September 5
    - The Courier-Journal Op-Ed "Justice Delayed, Denied", 2003 October 15
    - KCADP Memo on Legislative Planning, 2003 October 21
    - Major Findings by the Justice Delayed, Justice Denied Series, 2003 October 31
    - The Courier-Journal Op-Ed "Ending Delay's Injustice", 2003 November 2
    - Email from the Mailing List for People Working to Abolish the Death Penalty, "Discussing the Morality of Capital Punishment", 2003 November 12
    - "Bill Banning Death Penalty for Juveniles to be Introduced Monday" Release, 2004 February 8
    - Fellowship Rally Notice, 2004 March 4
    - Bulletin Announcement Postcard, 2004 March 4
    - March 17 Postcard, 2004 March 17
    - "Official Church Statements on Capital Punishment" Article, 2003
    - Police Lineup North Carolina, 2003
    - Regular Session Standing Committee Schedule, 2004
    - "Fiscal Tradeoffs: How the Death Penalty Impacts State and Local Budgets ", 2004
    - Juvenile Death Penalty Fact Sheet, 2004
    - Tribune on Illinois Reform, 2004
    - Death Penalty Information Center "New Voices: Victim's Family Requests Life Sentence For Death Row Inmate", 2004
    - Fact Sheet for Juvenile Bill, 2004
  - Abolition 2006
    - Letter to Dr. Nancy Jo Kemper, The Kentucky Council of Churches from Doug Stern, 2006 April 13
    - Notes from Meeting with Sr. Robbie Pentecost, 2006 April 18
    - Scanned Note from Doug Stern, 2006 April 23
    - Progress Report from Doug Stern, 2006 April 30
    - Doug and Maria Document "Bring the Death Penalty to Life in Your Parish" #1, 2006 May 16
    - Doug and Maria Document "Bring the Death Penalty to Life in Your Parish" #1, 2006 May 16
    - 30 Years After Gregg v. Georgia Grassroots Organizing Kit, 2006 May 22
    - KCADP Press Release Regarding New Educational Tool, 2006 September 11
    - Amnesty International Faith in Action Events Flyer, 2006 October 20
    - KCADP Letter to Incumbents, 2006 December 27
    - KCADP Letter to Non-Incumbents, 2006 December 27
    - KCADP "Weekend Memoir a Story of Hope" Article, 2006 September
  - Court Documents
    - Death Penalty Reinstated, House of Representatives, 1976 December 18 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Callins Dissent (vs. Blackmun), 1994 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Docs RE: Legislative Proposals, 1986-1992 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - General Assembly and Related Legislature, 1986-1990 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Legislature RE: Abuse and the Death Penalty, 1998-1994 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Legislation and Reports Regarding and Expungement, 2011-2013 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Clemency, Unknown (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Closing Argument The State of Illinois v. Nathan Leopold & Richard Loeb Delivered by Clarence Darrow, 1924 August 22
    - Supreme Court of Kentucky, Todd ICE v. Commonwealth of Kentucky, 1984 February 16
    - Govenor Patton Communication Request from Pat Delahanty, 2003 December 1
    - Petitition for a Writ of Certiorari, Jeffery Devan Leonard v. Thomas Simpson, 2007 April 2
    - Supreme Court of Kentucky, Shawn Windsor v. Commonwealth of Kentucky, 2010 August 26
    - Woodall v. Simpson, United States Court of Appeals, 2012 July 12
    - Unofficial Transcript ofRoger Dale Epperson v. Commonwealth of Kentucky, 2012 September 28
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky Court of Appeals, Tremel Smith, 2015 May 22
    - Affidavit of Kelly A. Gleason, 2004
  - Death Row Inmates
    - Stengel, Jasmin, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Death Row Inmate Letters, 1988-1996 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Gregory Wilson-Convict, 1989; 2009 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Bowling, Thomas-Death Row Inmate, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Supreme Court of Kentucky, Gregory Wilson v. Commonwealth of Kentucky, 1992 June 4
    - Supreme Court of Kentucky, Gregory Wilson v. Commonwealth of Kentucky, 1998 May 21
    - Death Penalty/Legal Concern Regarding Daniel Gordin, 2003 May 7
    - Letter to Govenor Fletcher from Associate Public Advocates, 2004 October 1
    - Petition to Vacate Thomas C. Bowling's Death Sentence Based on Mental Retardation, 2004 October 1
    - Letter to the Editor of The Courier-Journal from Douglas Stern, 2004 October 6
    - "Plea for Commutation of Death Sentence of Thomas Clyde Bowling Jr.", 2004 October 19
    - Letter to Govenor Fletcher from Capital Punishment Project and ACLU, 2004 October 25
    - Letter to Govenor Fletcher Re: Thomas Clyde Bowling from The Rutherford Institute, 2004 October 29
    - Letter to Dr. Clark Regarding a Request for a Ruling on the Question of Ethics, 2004 November 3
    - Document Regarding Discussion of Physcians Signing the Death Warrant, 2004 November 5
    - "Statement of Facts and Position" of Thomas Bowling Jr. Execution, 2004 November 5
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Thomas Clyde Bowling Jr. Executive Order from Govenor Fletcher, 2004 November 8
    - Email Message RE: Statements from Governor Ernie Fletcher and General Counsel to the Governor, John Roach, Regarding the Signed Death Warrant for Thomas Clyde Bowling Jr., 2004 November 8
    - "Execution Media Witnesses to Be Selected" Press Release from the Kentucky Department of Corrections, 2004 November 8
    - The Norwegian Medical Association's Letter Requesting Clemency in Regard to the Execution of Thomas Bowling Jr., 2004 November 8
    - "KY Bishops Saddened by Signing of Death Warrant" Press Release, 2004 November 9
    - "Doctor Fletcher in denial; abandons his professional oath" KCADP Press Release, 2004 November 9
    - Media Advisory for Press Conference of KCADP, 2004 November 12
    - Draft Letter Template to Govenor Fletcher, 2004 November 12
    - Email RE: "An Open Letter to Govenor Fletcher", 2004 November 14
    - "Religious Communitties Against the Death Penalty"'s Response to the Execution C. Bowling Jr., 2004 November 15
    - Statement for KCADP Press Conference, 2004 November 15
    - Email RE: Lack of Media Concerning the Govenor's Decision Regarding Thomas Bowling Jr., 2004 November 18
    - "Rally for Justice on the Kentucky State Capital Steps" Press Release, 2004 November 27
    - "An Appeal to Govenor Fletcher from a Fellow Physcian" Letter from Jonathan I. Groner MD, 2004 November 28
    - Doctor Arthur Zitrin's Commentary in LA Times, 2004 December 8
    - Letter to Dr. Clark Regarding a Grievance for the Medical Licensure Board, 2004 December 10
    - Danville Advocate Messenger, Letter to the Editor, 2005 January 12
    - Email News Report - "Medical Licensure Board to Hear Grievance Against Fletcher", 2005 January 12
    - United States Court of Appeals, Sixth Circuit, Gregory Wilson v. Phil Parker, Warden, 2007 September 11
    - Capital Defense Weekly "When Things Turn Ugly, Real Ugly", 2008 January 29
    - United States Court of Appeals, Sixth Circuit, Gregory Wilson v. Phil Parker, Warden, 2008 January 29
    - United States District Court, E.D. Kentucky. Central Division at Frankfort, Gregory Wilson v. John D. Rees et al Defendents, 2009 September 30
    - Motion to Prohibit Imposition of the Death Penalty, Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Gregory Wilson, 2010 April 14
    - Memorandum of Law in Support of Motion to Prohibit Imposition of the Death Penalty, Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Gregory Wilson, 2010 April 14
    - Appendix to Motion to Prohibit Imposition of the Death Penalty, Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Gregory Wilson, 2010 April 23
    - Motion to Prohibit Imposition of the Death Penalty, Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Gregory Wilson, Signed, 2010 April 23
    - Letter to Juliana Reed, Vice President of Government Affairs Hospira Regarding Sodium Thiopental (Pentothal), 2010 August 23
    - Executive Order, Death Warrant of Gregory Wilson, 2010 August 25
    - Memorandum to Govenor Steven L. Beshear Requesting the Death Warrants for Gregory Wilson, Robert Foley, and Ralph S. Baze Jr., 2010 August 25
    - Letter to Govenor Beshear from the Catholic Conference of Kentucky Regarding Execution of Gregory Wilson, 2010 August 30
    - Kentucky.com Article "Eliminate Death Penalty: Disparity of Sentences Unjustified" by Donald Vish, 2010 September 5
    - "Rotten Justice expires 9-16-2010", 2010 September 16
    - Draft for Discussion 8-31-10, Talking Points and Resource Guide, 2010 September 16
    - United States Court of Appeals, Sixth Circuit, Gregory Wilson v. John D. Rees, 2010 October 14
    - Letter from Patrick Delahanty Regarding Open Records Request, 2010 October 15
    - Notice of Withdrawal of Motion to Prohibit Imposition of the Death Penalty, Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Gregory Wilson, 2013 January 18
    - Exonerated Death Row Inmate Profile, Ben Kiper, 2013 January 25
    - Exonerated Death Row Inmate Profile, Edwin Chandler, 2013 January 26
    - Exonerated Death Row Inmate Profile, Herman May, 2013 January 26
    - Exonerated Death Row Inmate Profile, Jaqulynn Green, 2013 January 26
    - Exonerated Death Row Inmate Profile, Jason Girts, 2013 January 26
    - Exonerated Death Row Inmate Profile, Lacy Bedingfield Jr., 2013 January 26
    - Exonerated Death Row Inmate Profile, Michael VonAllmen, 2013 January 26
    - Exonerated Death Row Inmate Profile, Sam Plotnick, 2013 January 26
    - Exonerated Death Row Inmate Profile, Tim Smith, 2013 January 26
    - Exonerated Death Row Inmate Profile, William Gregory, 2013 January 26
    - Prayer Service on the Occasion of the Execution of Thomas Clyde Bowling, 2004 November
    - ACLU Media List, 2009 September
    - Letter to Governor for Signature of Members of Kentucky General Assembly, Discussion Draft, 2010 September
  - Execution Protocol
    - Statement on Behalf of the Associated Press, Kentucky AP Broadcasters, the Kentucky Press Association, the Courier-Journal, the Lexington Herald-Leader, and the Kentucky Broadcasters Association Given by Jon L. Fleischaker Regarding Kentucky's Proposed Execution Protocol, 2010 January 29
    - Chicago Tribune.com Article "Kentucky gets Supply on Key Execution Drug", 2011 February 22
    - 501 KAR 16-290, 2012 July 20
    - 501 KAR 16-310, 2012 July 20
    - 501 KAR 16-330, 2012 July 20
    - Statement of Consideration Relating to: 501 KAR 16:001, 16:290, 16:300, 16:310, 16:320, 16:330, 16:340, Amended After Comments, 2012 September 24
    - Photographs from Speakers, 2012 September 26
    - 501 KAR 16-330 Amendment after Filed, 2012 November 15
    - Statement of Consideration Relating to: 501 KAR 16:290 and 16:310 Not Amended After Comments 501 KAR 6:330 Amended After Comments, 2012 December 12
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky Franklin Circuit Court, Division I, Plantiffs' notice that a CR: 60.02 Motion, 2013 February 1
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky Franklin Circuit Court, Division I, Notice of Filing, 2013 February 1
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky Franklin Circuit Court, Division I, Plantiffs' Motion to Not Dismiss as Moot the CR 60.02 Motion, 2013 February 2
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky, Franklin Circuit Court Division I, Case No. 06-CI-00574, Memorandum of Law in Support of Second Amended Petition, 2013 February 6
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky, Franklin Circuit Court Division I, Case No. 06-CI-00574, Motion for Leave to File of Law in Support of Second Amended Petition, 2013 February 6
    - Commonwealth of Kentucky, Franklin Circuit Court Division I, Second Amended Petition for Declaratory Judgement, 2013 February 6
    - Courier-Journal.com Article "Ky. Asks Judge to Lift Ban on Executions", 2013 March 8
    - KCADP Letter to Ms.Barker Regarding the Response to Protocol, 2018 February 27
    - Guide to Commenting on Kentucky's 2012 Proposed Execution Protocols
    - ACLU Comments on Execution Protocols, 2012
    - Guide to Commenting on Kentucky's 2018 Proposed Execution Protocols
    - KCADP Protocol Bullet Points, 2018
  - High Cost as a Reason to Abolish
    - Death Penalty Costs, Monahan and Dieter, 2007; 2009 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Letter to Norman W. Lawson from Ed Monahan Regarding the Cost of the Death Penalty in Kentucly, 2009 February 25
    - "Smart on Crime: Reconsidering the Death Penalty in a Time of Economic Crisis" Report, 2009 October 17
    - "Testimony before the Pennsylvania Senate Government Management and Cost Study Commission" Report, 2010 June 7
    - "Testimony Submitted to the Kentucky Senate: Standing Committtee on Judiciary, Hearings on the Cost of the Death Penalty, 2012 March 1
    - Neal Speaking to the Senate, 2015 January 9
    - Average Costs Associated with an Aggravated First-Degree Murder Case Figure, 2015 January 9
    - Email from Ed Monahan Regarding the Cost of the Death Penalty, 2015 January 30
    - "Guest Column: The death penalty is bad investment" Article, 2015 July 12
    - "Guest Column: Tennesse needs to have a thorough conversation of the death penalty" Article, 2015 July 12
    - "The Cost of the Death Penalty in Marland" Report, 2008 March
  - Innocence Project